# Artem Tarasenko Front-end developer

I am Artem and I am a front-end developer with years of system administration experience. I finished an online MERN stack development Bootcamp and now focus on front-end development, involving Vanilla JS, React, Next Js, Node, Mongo DB, REST APIs, GraphQL, and when needed - Express, Mongo DB, Headless CMS.

# **Work History**

# Application developer

Primorsky Aquarium • Vladivostok • Russia 2017-08-16 - present

The Primorsky Aquarium, as a big scientific and exhibits center, has hundreds of devices installed in its exhibits areas that contain various applications with information for visitors. My role in the company is to maintain and enhance existing applications as well as develop new ones to improve visitors' experience. On this position, I started with my incomplete knowledge of web development, nevertheless completing my tasks successfully. Later in 2020, I completed web dev bootcamp, and ever since then I have been applying my newly acquired skills to fix all the problems that I have found during years of maintenance job, such as improving some applications or completely recreating others.

- Recreated web application used in the company for years without the ability to modify it as it was secured with SourceGuardian by a software development company (see "Species DB" app project on my personal website for further info).
- Designed and built an application to generate device's content instead of filling it manually (see "Species DB" app project on my personal website for further info)
- Designing and maintaining front end for local web applications.
- Support and development of new functionality for already existing
- Communication with the users regarding local web application improvement.

## **System Administrator** in various companies • Russia

09/2009 - 06/2017

### **Education**

2005-09-M.D. Computer Science

2010-07 Far Eastern State University - Russia

# **Certifications**

2019-09 IELTS: C1 CEFR level of English language

2020-11 Udemy: The Complete 2020 Web Development Bootcamp

#### **Contact**

#### **Address**

Vladivostok, Russia, 690080

#### Phone

79146707300

#### E-mail

Artem.tarasenko.g@gmail.com

#### LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/artemtaras enko

#### **Github**

https://github.com/artem-tarasenko

# **Skills**

HTML/CSS

Vanilla JS

SASS/SCSS

Tailwind CSS

# React **REST APIs** Github Next Js Express Js Mongo DB

# **Soft Skills**

Flexible thinking Creative

Motivated Ready to learn

Problem solver Social person